In case it's been a while since you've been sitting in a history class, here is what the Second Amendment actually says: "A well regulated Militia, being necessary to the security of a free State, the right of the people to keep and bear arms, shall not be infringed."
Por si hace mucho que no han estado en una clase de historia, esto es lo que dice la Segunda Enmienda, sorprendentemente dice: "Al ser una milicia bien regulada, necesaria para la seguridad de un estado libre, el derecho del pueblo a tener y portar armas, no será violado."
Meaning, the federal government could not infringe on the rights of citizens to participate in well-regulated militias. The Second Amendment was ratified 226 years ago. It was written in a time before the federal government's armed forces were among the most powerful in the world and when state militias were viewed as necessary to protect the states. Fast-forward 80 years, to 1871. The American Civil War had ended a few years prior, but a couple of Union officers had witnessed some pretty shoddy marksmanship on the battlefield. So in an attempt to prepare their men for any future conflicts, they founded the National Rifle Association to promote rifle practice. In short, the Second Amendment was written to ensure that our newly formed and fragile country had access to organized state militias. And the NRA's original mission was to ensure future soldiers had good aim. Someone could teach an entire course on how the next 150 years influenced the gun regulation conversations we're having in the United States and our interpretation of the Second Amendment. Almost every pivotal moment in our nation's history in one way or another influenced how we as a people manufacture, debate, regulate and feel about guns. A lot of change has occurred. As a matter of fact, it wasn't until 2008 that the Supreme Court ruled for the first time the Second Amendment protects an individual right to possess a firearm unconnected with service in a militia and to use that arm for traditionally lawful purposes, such as self-defense within the home. Within the home. This change over time is striking to me, because it reminds us that the interpretation of the Second Amendment and cultural attitudes about guns have changed over time. Which gives me hope they could change again. (Applause) It's an incredibly complex and dynamic history lesson, but it's not the lesson I'm here to teach today, because we don't have time. I'm not talking about time, the time that I have here to stand and speak. I'm talking about the fact we don't have time to lose. According to the CDC, over the last five years, on average, each day 96 people are killed by guns in the United States, and if we don't figure out how to answer my students' question soon, one of us could be next. So, if the question is, how do we stop this senseless violence, the best way I can think to answer is to look at multiple choice. You remember multiple-choice questions in high school, don't you? Let's start. Choice A: this will end when we hold gun manufacturers responsible for the deadliness of their products. It might surprise you to learn that we've actually thought about this before. Between 1998 and 2000, 30 counties and cities sued gun manufacturers, saying they should make their products safer and do a better job of tracking where their products are sold. In response, manufacturers argued that they had no direct liability for how their products were used. They said the stores who sold the guns and the owners who bought them were responsible should anything bad happen. In response to this and many other lawsuits, the NRA lobbied for the passage of the PLCAA, the Protection of Lawful Commerce in Arms Act.
Es decir, el gobierno federal no podría infringir los derechos de los ciudadanos a participar en milicias bien reguladas. La segunda enmienda fue ratificada hace 226 años. Fue escrita tiempo antes de que las fuerzas armadas del gobierno federal se hallaran entre las más poderosos del mundo, cuando las milicias del estado se consideraban necesarias para proteger los estados. Demos un salto, 80 años, hasta 1871. La guerra civil estadounidense había terminado unos años antes, pero un par de oficiales de la Unión habían sido testigos de punterías bastante mala en el campo de batalla. Así que para preparar a sus hombres para cualquier conflicto futuro, fundaron la Asociación Nacional del Rifle para fomentar el uso del rifle. En resumen, la Segunda Enmienda fue escrita para asegurar que nuestro país recién formado y frágil tuviera acceso a milicias estatales organizadas. Y la misión original de la NRA era asegurar que los futuros soldados tuvieran un buen objetivo. Cualquiera podría dar un curso completo sobre cómo los próximos 150 años influyeron en las conversaciones de regulación de armas que estamos teniendo en EE. UU. y nuestra interpretación de la Segunda Enmienda. Casi todos los momentos cruciales en la historia de nuestra nación de una forma u otra, influyeron en cómo nosotros como pueblo fabricamos, debatimos, regulamos y sentimos las armas de fuego. Se han producido muchos cambios. De hecho, no fue hasta 2008 que el Tribunal Supremo reguló por primera vez que la Segunda Enmienda protegiera el derecho individual a poseer un arma de fuego independientemente de estar al servicio de una milicia, y a usar ese arma para fines tradicionalmente legales, como la autodefensa dentro del hogar. ¡Dentro del hogar! Este cambio en el tiempo es sorprendente para mí, porque nos recuerda que la interpretación de la Segunda Enmienda y las actitudes culturales sobre las armas de fuego han cambiado con el tiempo. Lo cual me da la esperanza de que pueda cambiar otra vez. (Aplausos) Es una lección de historia dinámica e increíblemente compleja, pero no es la lección que pretendo enseñar hoy, porque no tenemos tiempo. No estoy hablando sobre el tiempo, el tiempo que tengo para estar aquí y hablar. Hablo del hecho de que no tenemos tiempo que perder. Según la CDC, en los últimos cinco años, de media, cada día 96 personas son asesinadas por armas de fuego en EE. UU., y si no descubrimos cómo responder a la pregunta de mis estudiantes pronto, uno de nosotros podría ser el siguiente. Y, si la pregunta es, cómo detenemos esta descabellada violencia, la mejor manera que se me ocurre responder es viendo las opciones múltiples. Recuerdan las preguntas de elección múltiple en el instituto, ¿no? Empecemos. Opción A: esto terminará cuando responsabilicemos a los fabricantes de armas por la letalidad de sus productos. Puede que les sorprenda saber que de hecho hemos pensado en esto antes. Entre 1998 y 2000 30 condados y ciudades demandaron a fabricantes de armas, alegando que deberían hacer sus productos más seguros, y un mejor seguimiento de dónde se vendían sus productos. En respuesta, los fabricantes alegaron que no tenían responsabilidad directa de cómo se usaban sus productos. Dijeron que las tiendas que vendían las armas y los dueños que los compraban eran responsables si algo malo sucedía. En respuesta a ésta y muchas otras demandas, la NRA presionó para la aprobación de la PLCAA, la Protección del Comercio Legal contra los Actos de Armas.
The PLCAA passed with bipartisan support in 2005 and entrusts gun manufacturers to design guns safely, stores to sell those guns responsibly and someone to own and use the gun responsibly. And so when 17 students and faculty die at my school, no one in this chain will assume responsibility. Let's take a look at another option, Choice B: this will end when we hold ourselves accountable and regulate the estimated 300 million guns available in America. Yes, voting is one of the best ways to take personal responsibility for gun violence. Making sure that our lawmakers are willing to pass commonsense gun reform is one of the most effective ways to get those 300 million guns under control. And also, gun owners can take personal initiative. If you own a gun, ask yourself: Do I have an extra gun I don't need? Could it fall into the wrong hands? Have I attended the latest training? Perhaps as a gun owner, you should also ask whether you have been taking care of your mental health? When it comes to gun violence, the mental health argument falls flat if we don't acknowledge our own personal vulnerabilities to mental illness. One in six Americans will struggle with mental illness. If we own a gun, we should be rigorously engaged in the upkeep of our emotional well-being so we don't pull a trigger in times of illness. Otherwise, we should seriously ask ourselves whether we really have the time and attention to own a gun. Perhaps for some of us it's time to lay down our arms. Then we have Choice C: this will end when we do a better job of taking care of each other. Many social issues affect why people buy and use guns. Sixty-two percent of US gun fatalities between 2012 and 2016 were suicides, yet we call people maniacs and psychos, shaming them. We are creating barriers for people that need help. Why are we embarrassing each other? Let's make it easier, not harder, for people to access better mental health care. What else? Sexism, racism and poverty affect gun ownership and gun-related fatalities. On average, it's estimated that 50 women were fatally shot each month between 2010 and 2014 due to domestic violence, and women are still dying in their homes. Let's empower women and give our young boys a chance to learn how to work out their conflicts and emotions with words, not weapons. And the "Washington Post" reported that last year, nearly 1,000 people were fatally wounded by on-duty police officers. Talk to Black Lives Matter and the police union about that. We need to tackle this. (Applause) At the end of the day, perhaps people won't feel the need to buy and use a gun when they all equally feel safe, healthy, respected and cared for. All right, discussion time is over. It's now time to answer the question. How do we stop this senseless violence? Is it Choice A, Choice B,
La PLCAA se aprobó con el apoyo bipartidista en 2005, y protege a los fabricantes de armas que las diseñan de forma segura, a los establecimientos que las venden responsablemente y a aquellos que las poseen y las usan con responsabilidad. Y así cuando 17 estudiantes y profesores mueren en mi escuela, nadie en esta cadena asumirá la responsabilidad. Echemos un vistazo a otra opción, opción B: esto terminará cuando nos hagamos responsables y regulemos los aproximadamente 300 millones de armas disponibles en EE. UU. Sí, votar es una de las mejores maneras de aceptar nuestra responsabilidad personal por la violencia armada. Asegurarnos de que nuestros legisladores están dispuestos a aprobar una reforma de armas racional, es una de las formas más efectivas de conseguir el control de esos 300 millones de armas. También los dueños de las armas puede tener iniciativa personal. Si poseen un arma, pregúntese: ¿Tengo un arma extra que no necesito? ¿Podría caer en las manos equivocadas? ¿He asistido a la última capacitación? Tal vez como propietarios de un arma, también deberían preguntarse si han estado cuidando su salud mental. Cuando se trata de violencia con armas, el argumento de la salud mental fracasa si no reconocemos nuestras propias vulnerabilidades personales a la enfermedad mental. Uno de cada seis estadounidenses luchará con la enfermedad mental. Si tenemos un arma, deberíamos comprometernos rigurosamente a mantener nuestro bienestar emocional para que no disparemos un gatillo cuando enfermemos. De lo contrario, deberíamos preguntarnos seriamente si realmente tenemos el tiempo y atención necesarios para poseer un arma. Quizás para algunos de nosotros es hora de dejar nuestras armas. Entonces tenemos la Opción C: terminará cuando mejoremos en cuidarnos los unos a los otros. Muchos problemas sociales provocan que la gente compre y use armas. El 62 % de las muertes por armas de fuego en EE. UU. entre 2012 y 2016 fueron suicidios. Sin embargo, seguimos llamándolos maníacos y psicópatas, avergonzándolos. Estamos creando barreras para las personas que necesitan ayuda. ¿Por qué nos avergonzamos los unos de los otros? Hagámoslo más fácil, no más difícil, para que puedan acceder a una mejor asistencia de salud mental. ¿Qué más? el sexismo, el racismo y la pobreza provocan la posesión de armas y las muertes relacionadas con ellas. De media, se estima que al mes 50 mujeres fueron mortalmente asesinadas entre 2010 y 2014, debido a violencia doméstica. Y siguen muriendo mujeres en sus hogares. Vamos a empoderar a las mujeres y a darles a nuestros hijos la oportunidad de aprender cómo resolver sus conflictos y emociones con palabras, no con armas. El "Washington Post" informó que el año pasado, casi 1000 personas resultaron fatalmente heridas por oficiales de policía en servicio. Hablen con Black Lives Matter y el sindicato policial sobre eso. Tenemos que hacer frente a esto. (Aplausos) Al final, tal vez, la gente no sentirá la necesidad de comprar y usar un arma cuando todos se sientan igualmente seguros, saludables, respetados y cuidados. Muy bien, el tiempo de debate ha acabado. Y es hora de responder la pregunta. ¿Cómo detenemos esta descabellada violencia? ¿Es la opción A, la opción B,
Choice C? Now, I know what you're all thinking. You remember that multiple-choice questions almost never end with just three possibilities. There's always that fourth, Choice D: all of the above. Maybe that's the answer here. Or maybe "all of the above" is too easy, and this is not an easy problem. It requires deep analytical thinking by all of us. So instead, I'm asking you to do your homework, write your own Choice D
o la opción C? Bueno, sé lo que todos están pensando. que las preguntas de respuestas múltiples casi nunca terminan con solo tres posibilidades. Siempre está esa cuarta, opción D: todas son correctas. Tal vez esa sea la respuesta aquí. O tal vez "todas son correctas" sea demasiado fácil, y este no es un problema fácil. Requiere una profunda reflexión analítica por parte de todos nosotros. Por tanto, lo que les estoy pidiendo es que hagan sus deberes, escriban su propia elección D
using supporting detail. And if you're not sure where to start, look to my students as role models. They are armed with incredible communication skills and a sense of citizenship that I find so inspiring. (Applause) These are public school kids engaged in the issue of gun regulation, and their endeavor has moved our hearts. And they shouldn't have to do this on their own. They're asking you,
usando toda la información. Y si no están seguros por dónde empezar, tomen a mis estudiantes como ejemplo. Están armados con increíbles destrezas comunicativas y un sentido de la ciudadanía que me parece muy inspirador. (Aplausos) Estos son los niños de las escuelas públicas comprometidos con los tema de la regulación de armas, y su esfuerzo ha conmovido nuestros corazones. Y no deberían tener que hacer esto por su cuenta. Les están pidiendo,
they're asking all of us, to get involved. This isn't a spectator sport. So what's the right answer? I don't know. Listen, I'm no gun control expert. I teach the humanities. To be human is to learn, and to be part of a civilization is to share your knowledge. This kind of honest, brave and sincere engagement is what I ask of my students, what I expect of myself as a teacher and what I demand of you now. Every one of you needs to do your homework. And then what? Humbly share your knowledge with each other. Please teach your family, teach your community, your city council, your state legislature. Teach Congress a lesson. Thank you. (Applause) Thank you. Thank you.
nos están pidiendo a todos, que nos involucremos. Esto no es un espetáculo. Por tanto, ¿cuál es la respuesta correcta? No lo sé. No soy una experta en control de armas. Yo enseño humanidades. Ser humano es aprender, y ser parte de una civilización es compartir el conocimiento. Este tipo de honestidad, de compromiso valiente y sincero es lo que les pido a mis alumnos, lo que espero de mí mismo como maestro y lo que les exijo a Uds. ahora. Cada uno de Uds. necesita hacer sus deberes. ¿Y después qué? Humildemente compartan sus conocimientos los unos a los otros. Por favor enséñenle a su familia, enseñen a su comunidad, su ayuntamiento, su legislación. Enseñen al Congreso una lección. Gracias. (Aplausos) Gracias. Gracias.